<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Delhi06</string>

    <string name="category_topspots">TOP SPOTS</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">RESTAURANTS</string>
    <string name="category_religious">RELIGIOUS</string>
    <string name="category_shopping">SHOPPING</string>
    
    <string name="Red_fort">Red Fort</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_summary">Iconic 1600s imperial residence &amp; museum</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_address">Netaji Subhash Marg, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi, Delhi 110006</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_description">Red Fort which is also known as Lal Qila was built by the
        Mughal Emperor, Shah Jahan. This monument represents the grandeur of the Mughal Court, which
        was constructed during the 17th century. Lal Qila was once the residential area of the Imperial
        Family of India. It was the capital of the Mughal rulers until 1857, when Bahadur Shah Zafar II
        went in exile after he was defeated by the Britishers.\n\nIn 2007, Red Fort was designated as
        a UNESCO World Heritage Site, which is situated in Old Delhi. The construction of this fort
        started in 1638 and it took over 10 years to complete the work in 1648. It was originally called
        as \'Qila-i-Mubarak\', meaning the blessed fort, as it was the royal residence of Mughals.\n\nDuring
        the British colonial rule, this fort was mainly used as a cantonment, which remained under the
        control of Indian Army after Indian Independence. This fort has various structures including
        Diwan-i-Aam, Diwan-i-Khas, Nahr-i-Behisht, Zenana, Mumtaz Mahal, Moti Masjid and Hayat Bakhsh Bagh.
        Red Fort also houses a famous Swatantra Sangrama Sangrahalaya or the Museum of the Independence Movement.
        There is also a Daawat Khana in Red Fort, which has been converted into a Tea House, where
        tourists can have tea and snacks.</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_no">+911123277705</string>

    <string name="Qutub_Minar">Qutub Minar</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_summary">5-storey victory tower with balconies</string>
    <string name="Qututb_Minar_address">Mehrauli, New Delhi, Delhi 110030</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_description">Qutub Minar is one of the tallest individual towers in the world,
        measuring about 234 ft in height. The construction work of Qutub Minar was commissioned by the
        ruler of Slave Dynasty, Qutubuddin-Aibak in 1199, which was later completed by his descendant
        Shams-ud-din-Iltutmish. He added three more storeys to this structure along with carved minarets.\n\nIt
        is situated in the Mehrauli region of Delhi, which is an ideal example of Indo-Islamic
        architecture style. This place also has a 7 m high iron pillar, which has not shown any sign
        of rust for more than 1,600 years.\n\nTravellers can also come across some other famous
        monuments like Ala-i-Darwaza and Ala-i-Minar situated within the complex. The southern gateway
        of Quwwat-ul-Islam that is the Ala-i-Darwaza was built in 1311 by Ala-ud-Din. Ala-i-Minar was
        built by Ala-ud-Din Khilji, which is situated to the north of Qutub Minar.</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_no">+911124698431</string>
</resources>
