<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Delhi06</string>

    <string name="category_topspots">TOP SPOTS</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">RESTAURANTS</string>
    <string name="category_religious">RELIGIOUS</string>
    <string name="category_shopping">SHOPPING</string>
    
    <string name="Red_fort">Red Fort</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_summary">Iconic 1600s imperial residence &amp; museum</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_address">Netaji Subhash Marg, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi, Delhi 110006</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_description">Red Fort which is also known as Lal Qila was built by the
        Mughal Emperor, Shah Jahan. This monument represents the grandeur of the Mughal Court, which
        was constructed during the 17th century. Lal Qila was once the residential area of the Imperial
        Family of India. It was the capital of the Mughal rulers until 1857, when Bahadur Shah Zafar II
        went in exile after he was defeated by the Britishers.\n\nIn 2007, Red Fort was designated as
        a UNESCO World Heritage Site, which is situated in Old Delhi. The construction of this fort
        started in 1638 and it took over 10 years to complete the work in 1648. It was originally called
        as \'Qila-i-Mubarak\', meaning the blessed fort, as it was the royal residence of Mughals.\n\nDuring
        the British colonial rule, this fort was mainly used as a cantonment, which remained under the
        control of Indian Army after Indian Independence. This fort has various structures including
        Diwan-i-Aam, Diwan-i-Khas, Nahr-i-Behisht, Zenana, Mumtaz Mahal, Moti Masjid and Hayat Bakhsh Bagh.
        Red Fort also houses a famous Swatantra Sangrama Sangrahalaya or the Museum of the Independence Movement.
        There is also a Daawat Khana in Red Fort, which has been converted into a Tea House, where
        tourists can have tea and snacks.</string>
    <string name="Red_fort_no">+91 11 2327 7705</string>

    <string name="Qutub_Minar">Qutub Minar</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_summary">5-storey victory tower with balconies</string>
    <string name="Qututb_Minar_address">Mehrauli, New Delhi, Delhi 110030</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_description">Qutub Minar is one of the tallest individual towers in the world,
        measuring about 234 ft in height. The construction work of Qutub Minar was commissioned by the
        ruler of Slave Dynasty, Qutubuddin-Aibak in 1199, which was later completed by his descendant
        Shams-ud-din-Iltutmish. He added three more storeys to this structure along with carved minarets.\n\nIt
        is situated in the Mehrauli region of Delhi, which is an ideal example of Indo-Islamic
        architecture style. This place also has a 7 m high iron pillar, which has not shown any sign
        of rust for more than 1,600 years.\n\nTravellers can also come across some other famous
        monuments like Ala-i-Darwaza and Ala-i-Minar situated within the complex. The southern gateway
        of Quwwat-ul-Islam that is the Ala-i-Darwaza was built in 1311 by Ala-ud-Din. Ala-i-Minar was
        built by Ala-ud-Din Khilji, which is situated to the north of Qutub Minar.</string>
    <string name="Qutub_Minar_no">+91 11 2469 8431</string>

    <string name="India_Gate">India Gate</string>
    <string name="India_Gate_summary">1920s triumphal arch &amp; war memorial</string>
    <string name="India_Gate_address">Rajpath, India Gate, New Delhi, Delhi 110001</string>
    <string name="India_Gate_description">India Gate is situated on the Raj Path and was commissioned
        by Sir Edwin Lutyens for paying reverence to the Indian Soldiers, who died during the First
        World War. The huge walls of India Gate reveal more than 90,000 names of the soldiers who lost
        their lives during the war. This structure was completed in 1931 and was originally called as
        the All India War Memorial. It is mainly a 42 m tall gate that is surrounded by beautiful
        fountains and gardens.\n\nAt the base of this structure, there is an eternal flame called
        \'Amar Jawan Jyoti\', which pays tribute to the soldiers who died during the Indian Independence.
        There is also a boat club and children\'s park near India Gate that are situated on Rajpath. </string>
    <string name="India_Gate_no">+91 11 2464 7005</string>

    <string name="Humayun_Tomb">Humayun\'s Tomb</string>
    <string name="Humayun_Tomb_summary">Palatial 16th-century tomb of Humayun</string>
    <string name="Humayun_Tomb_address">Mathura Road, Opp. Dargah Nizamuddin, New Delhi, Delhi 110013</string>
    <string name="Humayun_Tomb_description">Humayun\'s Tomb is the famous tomb of Humayun, who was the
        Mughal Emperor. The construction of this tomb was commissioned by Humayun\'s wife, Hamida Banu
        Begum in 1562. It was designed by Mirak Mirza Ghiyath, a Persian architect and it is situated
        in Nizamuddin East. The entire structure is built using red sandstone, which was declared as
        a UNESCO World Heritage Site in 1993.\n\nThere is a huge garden in the complex, which has
        fountains, pools, trees and benches to sit. Tourists can also see the Char Bagh inside the
        complex which have quadrilateral Persian style layout. Babar\'s Tomb is also situated near
        the main tomb of Humayun inside the complex.</string>
    <string name="Humayun_Tomb_no">+91 11 2435 5275</string>

    <string name="Bukhara">Bukhara - ITC Maurya</string>
    <string name="Bukhara_summary">10-time winner of the \'Times Food Award\'</string>
    <string name="Bukhara_address">Hotel ITC Maurya, Sardar Patel Marg, Diplomatic Enclave, Chanakyapuri, New Delhi 110021</string>
    <string name="Bukhara_description">The food at Bukhara is cooked in clay ovens or tandoor in the
        traditional style of the Indian North-West Frontier region. This style of cooking requires
        great expertise on the part of the chefs, since the meat is not accompanied by any sauce or
        gravy, but is only pre-marinated and cooked before serving. It takes a Chef years of meticulous
        training and dedication to master the technique of the art of making the breads that are a
        vital part of the cuisine, or to acquire the ability to gauge spices, mix marinades, and the
        most vital of all, to judge the heat of the tandoor and the time necessary for each dish to
        be perfectly cooked.\n\nThe world renowned Dal Bukhara, a combination of whole black lentils
        (urad dal), tomatoes, ginger and garlic, is cooked and simmered over slow coal fires of the
        tandoor overnight for 18 hours at a stretch! It is sure to be the longest cooked lentil in
        the world!\n\nAnother unique feature of the cuisine is the use of prime cuts of meat,
        marinated with the choicest of spices and skilfully cooked on high heat, while retaining
        their tender moistness.</string>
    <string name="Bukhara_no">+91 11 2611 2233</string>

    <string name="Karim">Karim\'s</string>
    <string name="Karim_summary">Long established (Est.1913) chain cooking up a range of traditional Mughlai dishes</string>
    <string name="Karim_address">16, Gali Kababian, Jama Masjid, New Delhi 110006</string>
    <string name="Karim_description">Karim\'s Hotel or Karim\'s is a historic restaurant located near
        Jama Masjid, Gali Kababian, Old Delhi, Delhi. Established in 1913, the restaurant has been
        described as \"synonymous with this area\" (Old Delhi) and \"arguably the city\'s most famous
        culinary destination\".\n\n.In mid 19th century, Mohammed Aziz was a cook in the royal court
        of Mughal Emperor, however after the Bahadur Shah Zafar was exiled, he left the city for Meerut
        and later Ghaziabad. However, in 1911, when Delhi Durbar was held for the coronation of the
        King George V, one of Aziz\'s son Haji Karimuddin moved back to Delhi with an innovative idea
        of opening a Dhaba to cater the people coming from all over India to join the coronation.
        Haji Karimuddin started the Dhaba selling just two items of Alu gosht (mutton with potatoes)
        and Daal (lentil curry) served with Rumali Roti.\n\nIn 1913, Haji Karimuddin established the
        Karim Hotel in Gali Kababian, near Jama Masjid, Delhi saying, \"I want to earn fame and money
        by serving the royal food to the common man\". The restaurants opened its first branch in 1990s
        in Nizamuddin West, followed by Kailash Colony, Noida, Gurgaon and at Kamla Nagar, all in
        Delhi NCR region.\n\nToday, the fourth generation is running the show with Karim Hotels Pvt.
        Ltd. at Jama Masjid, a Restaurant called Dastar Khwan-E-Karim at Nizamuddin West New Delhi. </string>
    <string name="Karim_no">+91 99717 40634</string>

    <string name="Motimahal">Moti Mahal</string>
    <string name="Motimahal_summary">"Inventor of Butter Chicken &amp; Dal Makhani</string>
    <string name="Motimahal_address">3703, Netaji Subhash Marg, Daryaganj, New Delhi 110002</string>
    <string name="Motimahal_description">The story of Moti Mahal Delux dates back to year 1920, when
        Mokha Singh Lamba started a small eatery called Moti Mahal in Peshawar, British India. Kundan
        Lal Gujral worked for Mokha Singh at Moti Mahal in Peshawar. Moti Mahal was the first to dig
        up a tandoor right in the middle of the eatery and since then Peshawar was introduced to the
        culinary art of tandoori chicken by them. This was a success and soon there was in demand for
        Tandoori at social gatherings and wedding feasts where they would use an improvised tandoor.
        \n\nAfter the partition of India in 1947, Kundan Lal Gujral, a Punjabi Hindu, fled to Delhi with
        his family. Uncertainty faced them as they had neither money nor the resources to start afresh
        in life. They dropped off in Delhi to try their luck. Roaming the streets, they chanced upon
        an abandoned thara in Daryaganj, and then considered a newer part of Old Delhi. Kundan Lal
        Gujral then started Moti Mahal, Daryaganj with another partner, Thakur Das Mago. Moti Mahal
        further went on to invent butter chicken and dal makhani. This brought about a revolution in
        taste and a place on the International Gourmet Map.\n\nThus was born the Moti Mahal Restaurant,
        which contributed significantly to putting India on the food map of the world. Indian leaders
        like Jawahar Lal Nehru, Indira Gandhi,Zakir Hussain among various foreign dignitaries like
        Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy and Mohammad Reza Pahlavi. have visited Moti Mahal to sample
        Kundan\'s innovations – its tandoori delicacies on various occasions.  M. Maulana Azad, the
        great Muslim leader, reportedly told the Shah of Iran that while in India he must make two
        visits - to the Taj Mahal and Moti Mahal. Later in 1970\'s Kundan Lal’s son Mr Nand Lal \'Bila\'
        Gujral, upon the exit of Thakur Das Mago from the partnership, expanded Moti Mahal Delux in
        south Delhi to establish Moti Mahal Delux Chain of Restaurants.</string>
    <string name="Motimahal_no">+91 98104 41938</string>

    <string name="Wengers">Wenger\'s</string>
    <string name="Wengers_summary">Enduring cafe serving a range of sweet patisserie and international snack dishes for over 75 years</string>
    <string name="Wengers_address">A-16, Middle Circle, Connaught Place, New Delhi, Delhi 110001</string>
    <string name="Wengers_description">“Wenger\'s saw Connaught Place being built brick by brick,” says
        Charanjeet Singh the confectionary’s manager since 1965. Owned by a young Swiss couple named
        Wenger, this two-floored bakery, restaurant and café was popular among British bureaucrats,
        foreign diplomats and Indian royalty until Independence, in 1947. In its early days, it was
        also a popular venue for expat weddings, ballroom dances and official dinners.\n\nIn the 1920s,
        cakes and pastries were unknown commodities for most Indians. For the past 75 years Wenger\'s has
        maintained its standard of quality and service and has been introducing new items regularly
        to cater to the ever changing tastes of its customers. Few cafés, have survived to see the rise
        and fall of the British Empire. Wenger\'s has.</string>
    <string name="Wengers_no">+91 093100 54358</string>

    <string name="Laxmi">Laxmi Narayan Mandir</string>
    <string name="Laxmi_summary">Large Hindu temple covers 7.5 acres &amp; features numerous shrines, fountains &amp; a garden</string>
    <string name="Laxmi_address">Mandir Marg, Near Golmarket, Gole Market, New Delhi, Uttar Pradesh 110001</string>
    <string name="Laxmi_description">Lakshmi Narayan Temple is commonly known as the Birla Mandir
        which is situated at Mandir Marg near Connaught Place in New Delhi. This temple was constructed
        in 1938 by the famous industrialist, B.D. Birla. The temple was built for honouring Goddess
        Lakshmi, who is considered to be the goddess of wealth along with her husband Lord Vishnu.
        There are many other small temples, fountains and gardens inside the temple complex.\n\nIt is
        a very old temple which was inaugurated by Mahatma Gandhi. Janmashtami, the birthday of Lord
        Krishna is celebrated at a grand level in this temple. Other important festivals celebrated
        in this temple are Diwali and Ram Navmi. </string>
    <string name="Laxmi_no">+91 11 2336 3637</string>

    <string name="Bangla">Bangla Sahib Gurudwara</string>
    <string name="Bangla_summary">Sikh house of worship with a golden dome &amp; a pool of water with purported healing properties</string>
    <string name="Bangla_address">Ashoka Road, Connaught Place, Next to Grand Post Office, New Delhi 110001</string>
    <string name="Bangla_description">Gurudwara Bangla Sahib is situated next to the Gol Dak Khana in
        Connaught Place. It is a holy place of Sikh worship which is open to people of all castes, creeds
        and faiths. There is a sacred pond inside this gurudwara, where devotees take bath. This gurudwara
        is managed by the Delhi Sikh Gurudwara Management Committee, which also celebrates the birth
        of Guru Sri Harkrishan Sahib.\n\nThe committee also celebrates death anniversary of Maharaja
        Ranjit Singh ji. To the eastern side of the gurudwara, there is a community kitchen or langar,
        where devotees cook food and serve to the people. The main gurudwara has a gold-plated dome
        and white facade exterior along with a prayer hall. It also has an art gallery, library,
        hospital, a Baba Baghel Singh Museum and a higher secondary school for girls.</string>
    <string name="Bangla_no">+91 11 2334 0174</string>

    <string name="Jama">Jama Masjid</string>
    <string name="Jama_summary">17th-century, red sandstone Mughal-style mosque with a 25,000 capacity &amp; 40m high minarets</string>
    <string name="Jama_address">Meena Bazaar, Jama Masjid, Chandni Chowk, New Delhi 110006</string>
    <string name="Jama_description">Jama Masjid was commissioned by the Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan which
        is considered to be one of the biggest mosques in Old Delhi. The floor of the mosque has been
        totally covered with white and black marbles that give the look of prayer mat as in Mohammedan
        culture. It is situated on one of the busiest streets of Old Delhi, Chawri Bazaar Road.\n\nThe
        outer courtyard of this mosque can hold around 25,000 people at a time, which is rectangular
        in shape and measures 75 m by 66 m. This mosque was constructed with the efforts of more than
        5,000 workers, over a period of 7 years in 1628. The cost incurred during that period was about
        10 lakhs rupees.</string>
    <string name="Jama_no">+91 11 2336 5358</string>

    <string name="Lotus">Lotus Temple</string>
    <string name="Lotus_summary">Temple with a Lotus flower like design</string>
    <string name="Lotus_address">Lotus Temple Rd, Shambhu Dayal Bagh, Bahapur, Kalkaji, New Delhi 110019</string>
    <string name="Lotus_description">Lotus Temple is situated near Kalkaji in Delhi which is the only
        Bahai Temple in Asia. This temple was designed by Fariborz Sahba, which has a half floating
        lotus as the main structure along with white petals made of marble. It measures around 35 m
        in height and is located amidst 9 pools and huge lawns. There is a big prayer hall inside
        this temple which is used by the devotees for meditation.\n\nTourists can visit this temple
        during evening, when the entire structure is illuminated, giving it a golden glow. The temple
        building was fully completed in 1986 and is open to people of all faiths, creeds and castes.
        It remains closed on Mondays and does not have any admission fees for the visitors.</string>
    <string name="Lotus_no">+91 11 2644 4029</string>

    <string name="CP">Connaught place</string>
    <string name="CP_summary">5th most expensive office market in the world</string>
    <string name="CP_address">Connaught Place, New Delhi, Delhi 110001</string>
    <string name="CP_description">Connaught Place is the commercial hub of New Delhi, which is popular
        among tourists for shopping. It was built in 1931 and was inspired from well planned and well
        structured Victorian style of architecture. Connaught Place is divided into two zones, inner
        circle and outer circle. It was designed by Robert Tor Russell and W. H. Nicholls, and was
        named after the Duke of Connaught, who was the member of British royal family.\n\nOf the two
        circles of Connaught Place, Inner Circle has numerous international brands, restaurants,
        eateries and bars and bookshops. The place is also popular for buying handicraft items from
        the nearby location, Janpath.\n\nAll the branches of major nationalised and international banks
        along with the offices of tour operators and emporiums are present in Connaught Place. There
        is also a central park, located at the centre of Connaught Place, which offers a beautiful
        environment.\n\nConnaught place is located in the heart of the city and can be reached with
        the availability of various modes of transport such as bus, auto-rickshaw and metro.</string>
    <string name="CP_no">0</string>

    <string name="Khan">Khan Market</string>
    <string name="Khan_summary">Khan Market (Est.1951) has been ranked as the costliest retail location in India</string>
    <string name="Khan_address">Khan Market, Rabindra Nagar, New Delhi, Delhi 110003</string>
    <string name="Khan_description">Classy and posh, Khan Market is a favourite of the expat and
        diplomatic community. It was originally allocated as seed land to immigrants from the North-West
        Frontier Province after the partition of India. Today, it is a popular shopping destination
        in Delhi. It is a large U-shaped market with two parallel \'U\'s and some extensions. You will
        find excellent book shops, up-market boutiques, opticians, grocers, tailors, brand showrooms,
        lifestyle stores, etc here &amp; There are also a couple of boutiques selling up-market household
        furnishings. Across the road are shops that specialize mainly in lighting. You will also find
        many eating joints: cafes, restaurants, bakeries and street-food corners.\n\nKhan Chacha is
        a landmark: its tikkas and seekhs are a rage with the crowd. Amrapali is famous for its silver
        jewellery. Ranna Gill makes two major fashion statements each year with her summer and winter lines</string>
    <string name="Khan_no">0</string>

    <string name="Sarojini">Sarojini-Nagar Market</string>
    <string name="Sarojini_summary">One of Delhi\'s biggest markets and a destination for every girl who\'s out on a hunt for trendy clothes at killer prices</string>
    <string name="Sarojini_address">Sarojini Nagar, South Delhi, New Delhi, Delhi 110023</string>
    <string name="Sarojini_description">Sarojini Nagar Market (or SN, as locals know it) is Delhi\'s
        most famous and best known Flea Market. The market is like a living organism which has a
        positive pulsating energy of its own that can be felt as soon as one enters the Sarojini Nagar
        Market. The market is known for export excess goods which are branded and yet cost a lot less
        than the showroom price.\n\nSarojini Nagar Market is a great retreat for lovers of haggling
        and for whom bargaining is a stress buster, it is a full-fledged flea market in this regard.
        It is an unspoken understanding that 40-50 percent of the price can be bargained for. The sellers
        will ensure that no matter what the price tag says, a reasonable price is negotiated.\n\nThere
        is a huge variety of merchandise from brands like Vero Moda, Forever 21, Mango, Zara, Levis,
        LP etc. which can be purchased at very low prices; being export excess. The sellers employ
        many methods to woo the customers like having jokers in front of their shops and people
        shouting extremely witty slogans to lure the customers in.\n\nThe “gully” with the arch in
        front of the vegetable market has a lot of variety of dresses and other dress items for women.
        You must check the size of the clothes you want to buy here before purchasing them because
        the size tags can sometimes be deceiving. Also do wash the clothes once before wearing them
        as we all know the conditions in which they are put on display for the whole day.</string>
    <string name="Sarojini_no">0</string>

    <string name="Chowk">Chandini Chowk</string>
    <string name="Chowk_summary">One of the oldest and busiest markets in Old Delhi</string>
    <string name="Chowk_address">Chandni Chowk, New Delhi, Delhi 110006</string>
    <string name="Chowk_description">Chandni Chowk is considered as one of the oldest and busiest
        markets in North Delhi. It is situated in the Shahjahanabad area between Red Fort and Fatehpuri
        Masjid. On both sides of the wide Chandni Chowk streets are historical residential areas
        flanked by narrow lanes (galis).\n\nIt houses many temples like Shri Digambar Jain Lal Mandir
        and Hindu Gauri Shankar Temple. Apart from these temples, it also has a Gurudwara namely
        Gurudwara Sis Ganj Sahib. There exist 2 mosques in this place, namely Muslim Sunehri Masjid
        and Muslim Fatehpuri Masjid.\n\nIt is counted among the biggest wholesale and retail markets
        of India. It was built in 1650 when Mughal Emperor Shah Jahan shifted his capital to Delhi
        and is around 300 years old. It is believed that the Emperor\'s daughter Jahanara, designed
        this market, where an array of shops were established in a half-moon shape.\n\nChandni Chowk
        is famous all over in India for its eating joints and some of these are very old. Tourists
        can reach this place as the by travelling by bus to the Inter State Bus Terminal that is
        located very close to it. </string>
    <string name="Chowk_no">0</string>

</resources>
